彼得：机器人飞机正在变得无处不在。现在整个班级都非常复杂
Peter: Robotic aircraft are becoming ubiquitous. There's a whole class now of quite sophisticated
玩具你可以去商店购买几百美元。一般来说，有
toys you can go and buy from the shop for a few hundred bucks. Generally, there are
四旋翼机。您可以使用iPhone控制它们。你可以飞起来。您
quad rotor machines. You can control them with your iPhone. You can fly them up. You
可以看出邻居的围栏。你可以看看邻居的窗口。所以，这项技术
can look out the neighbor's fence. You can look in neighbor's window. So, this technology
开始引起人们对隐私的严重关注。道格，什么呢
is starting to cause people serious concerns with respect to privacy. So Doug, what does
关于隐私的道德说法？
ethics say about privacy?
道格：隐私的构建是一种现代的结构。
Doug: The construct of privacy is a modern construct.
彼得：好的。我们没有使用隐私？
Peter: Okay. We didn't use to have privacy?
道格：嗯，这是文化定义的。
Doug: Well, it's culturally defined.
道格：换句话说，我认为今天在21世纪的澳大利亚是私密的，你是什么
Doug: In other words, what I consider private today in 21st century Australia and what you
在1850年的伦敦会考虑私人，这是完全不同的。我们选择的是什么
would consider private in 1850 London, it's quite different. What we choose in terms of
隐私是不同的。它随时间和地点而变化。然而-
privacy is different. It's contextual over time and place. However--
彼得：那么，这不是一个基本的基本原则吗？
Peter: So, it's not a fundamental underlying principle?
道格：不。
Doug: No.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：不，绝对不是。隐私不是。它建立在自由民主和国家
Doug: No, absolutely not. Privacy is not. It's founded in liberal democracy and the
个人有权选择并拥有自己的空间。美国人是唯一的，
right of the individual to choose and have their own space. The Americans are the only,
我认为他们是唯一拥有财产权的文化。拥有财产权
I think they're the only culture that has right to property. With the right to property
来隐私权。但是，隐私程度当然是正确的
comes right to privacy. But the degree of privacy, of course, is being argued right
现在在澳大利亚获取数据。
now in Australia in terms of access to data.
彼得：当然。
Peter: Absolutely.
道格：是的。因此，在道德方面，它又回到了那些基本职责或者
Doug: Yes. So, in terms of ethics, it goes back again to those fundamental duties or
那些自治的基本概念。因此，我们在自治方面拥有自由度。
those fundamental concepts of autonomy. So, we have levels of freedom in terms of autonomy.
所以，这些级别从自由，当然，从克制到选择的自由，
So, those levels go from freedom, of course, of restraint down to the freedom of choice,
然后通知原因，知情选择，最后，基于认可的选择
then to informed reason, informed choice and lastly, the choice based on the recognition
道德价值观。因此，这些是在道德方面至关重要的自治方面。现在，
of moral values. So, those are areas in terms of autonomy that are critical in ethics. Now,
如果你失去了隐私，就道德而言，这里唯一的道德论点是它如何影响
if you lose your privacy, in terms of ethics, the only ethical argument here is how it affects
你的个人自主权来做出决定。但隐私当然不是道德问题，
your individual autonomy to make decisions. But privacy is certainly not an ethical issue,
这是一个文化问题。
it's a cultural issue.
彼得：所以，如果它压缩你的风格或改变你能做的事情，那么这是一个道德问题。
Peter: So, if it's cramping your style or it's changing what you can do, then it's an ethical issue.
道格：是的。
Doug: It is.
道格：因为它影响了你的选择权。同样，这是一个现代的结构
Doug: Because it's affecting your power of choice. Again, that's a modern construct is
隐私。这是一个现代建筑。这是完全不同的。例如，在罗马时代你
privacy. It's a modern construct. It's quite different. For example, in Roman times you
今天可能会和其他人一起洗澡-或者你不洗澡-和其他人一起洗澡
may take a shower - or you don't take a shower you take baths - with other people, today
我们有自己的浴室。但隐私......当我和五个孩子和两个卧室一起长大...
we have our own bathrooms. But privacy… when I grew up with five kids and two bedrooms…
现在它是一个不同的结构，对吧？
it's a different construct now, right?
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yes.
道格：这是文化决定的。
Doug: It's culturally determined.
彼得：有些人说隐私是一个概念
Peter: There are some people who say that privacy is a concept that is just going to
走开，我们应该习惯它。
go away and we should just get used to it.
道格：是的。
Doug: Yes.
彼得：特别是关于我们的在线存在和身份。
Peter: Particularly, with respect to our online existence and identities.
道格：是的，是的。自治是问题，而不是隐私。
Doug: Yes, yes. Autonomy is the issue, not privacy.